KOUADJO AMOS YANN EMMANUEL AGRE

Ivorian | Nairobi, Kenya | +254799673045 yannagre1997@gmail.com | LinkedIn: Yann Emmanuel AGRE

SUMMARY

Passionate individual about culture diversity and dynamics with over 5 years' experience learning and maturing in different nations coupled with a dozen years of experience in IT support and infrastructure management. Involved in different projects of providing translation and interpretation for several individuals and businesses as well as consulting for SMEs and Start-ups and tutoring of upcoming software development talents.

SKILLS

Translation Customer Support Mentoring
Interpretation Research Ability Public Speaking
Versatile Design Thinking Digital Marketing
Adaptive Web Development Software Development

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Strathmore University – Nairobi, Kenya Bachelor in Business Information Technology September, 2020 - Present

Relevant Coursework: Project Management, Web Development, Programming, Database Management

Academic standing: B

Strathmore University – Nairobi, Kenya Diploma in Business Information Technology **January**, 2019 – October, 2021

Relevant Coursework: Software Engineering, Programming, Computer Network, Project Management **Academic standing**: Merit (B)

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Translator Nairobi, Kenya

March, 2024

- Translating social media contents from English to French
- Translating presentation contents from English to French
- Translating academic research papers

French & English Translator/Interpret Strathmore University – Nairobi, Kenya

February, 2022 – Mars, 2022

- Providing translation of documents for communication, logistics and operation purpose
- Assisting in interpreting discussion points from French to English and from English to French
- Bridging communication between government authorities from Côte d'Ivoire and the institution authorities
- Preparing materials in French and in English for different meetings and presentations

Jr. Administrative and IT Manager Siloam Ophthalmic Centre – Abidjan, Côte d'Ivoire

October, 2020 – December, 2020

- Managed daily administrative operations e.g., record of expenses, patients' details and medical inventory
- Maintained the IT equipment
- Mentored staff on usage of IT equipment
- Developed a quotation format for patients' invoices

Assistant French Teacher Home Tutoring — Nairobi, Kenya

Juin, 2020 - Juillet, 2020

- Preparing teaching materials for different lessons for English-speaking individuals learning French
- Assisting the teacher with IT issues for online lessons
- Establishing cooperatively learning outline for French lessons

Jr. Consulting Web Developer Digital Oasis Itd – Nairobi, Kenya

- Collaborated closely with the development team on a variety of projects
- Provided support to clients
- Mentored staff from the development team
- Trained in installing Mifos X platform

Technical Support Consultant Siloam Ophthalmic Centre – Abidjan, Côte d'Ivoire

September, 2018 - November, 2018

- Successfully achieved the creation of a database to store patients' details
- Contributed to the management of the database and mentoring of the staff

Jr. Lab Manager

September, 2013 - June, 2015

Methodist Secondary School of Cocody – Abidjan, Côte d'Ivoire

- Established guidelines and monitored the use of the lab devices by other pupils and staff of the school
- Managed the lab's equipment
- Trained in basic graphic design

Jr. Lab Manager

September, 2009 - June, 2013

Methodist Secondary School of Plateau – Abidjan, Côte d'Ivoire

- Established guidelines and monitored the use of the lab's equipment by other pupils and staff of the school
- Managed the lab's equipment
- Trained in maintenance, installation and management of the lab's equipment

CERTIFICATES & ACHIEVEMENTS

University of Toronto – Coursera

Mind Control: Managing your Mental Health during COVID-19

University of Michigan - Coursera

<u>Introduction to Programming using Python</u> Python Data Structures

LANGUAGES

French - Native English - Fluent German - Beginner

HOBBIES

Football/Soccer (Among the team Art Production (Movies, Traveling leaders, playing different roles and positions on & off the field)

Traveling

Music, Reading books)

REFEREES

Richard Arina Okonda Nairobi, Kenya

Lecturer, French Department, Strathmore University

Email: richmondarina@yahoo.com / Tel.: +254(0)733402912

Isaac Kigen Kipkosgei

Lecturer, School of Computing and Engineering Science, Strathmore University

Email: ikigen@strathmore.edu / Tel.: +254(0)722408508

Moses Gitonga Ntiritu Nairobi, Kenya

Director & Founder, Digital Oasis Ltd

Email: ntiritumusa@qmail.com / Tel.: +254(0)717876536

Nairobi, Kenya